# Indranil Ray

Pune +91-8055279618 neal.welcome@gmail.com in https://www.linkedin.com/in/indranildev6665 https://twitter.com/nealdev6665

Senior Software Engineer specialized in web application development. Passionate, responsible and committed with get-it-done, on time-spirit with more than 5 years of experience in designing, implementing and adapting technically sophisticated web applications using PHP, Python, JavaScript, SQL and other Open Source Technologies. Experience with AGILE methodologies and all other stages of development.

# **Programming Languages and Tools**

| Backend   | FET & Markup      | Database   | Framework     | OS      | Tools    |
|-----------|-------------------|------------|---------------|---------|----------|
| Python    | Javascript & Ajax | MySQL      | Odoo -11      | Windows | Docker   |
| PHP       | JQuery            | PostgreSql | Django        | Ubuntu  | Git      |
| Core Java | HTML              |            | CodeIgniter   |         | AWS      |
| С         | CSS               |            | PHP Unit      |         | RabbitMQ |
| C++       | Bootstrap         |            | Smarty & Twig |         | Celery   |
|           | XML               |            | Unittest      |         | Pycharm  |
|           |                   |            | Wordpress     |         | PhpStorm |
|           |                   |            | ORM           |         | Jira     |

#### **Skills**

- Database Designing and Optimization.
- Containerization and AWS.
- CRM and CMS Platform
- REST API Development and Integration,
- Programming.
- Responsible Web Design.
- Web Application Development and scaling.
- Agile Methodologies.
- Web scrapping.

# **Experience**

OCTOBER 2016 - PRESENT

# Senior Software Engineer / Cybage Software, Pune

Key contributors to start up company's fast evolution to sell their niche product by offering a full solution suite marketed to **Retail** for their **ERP** and **Health Care** Industries.

- Led development and enhancement of CRM powered with ODOO (Python 3.6) by providing complete customization. Perform Test Driven Approach and incremental release for better scalability of system.
- **Elicit, collect and analyze requirements with clients**. Take part in backlog grooming and sprint task creation.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize scalability. Code linting, coverage and writing Python Test Cases is part of development protocol.
- Complete detailed programming and development task for front end as well as challenging back end server code.
- **Collaborate with clients and designers** to create clean interface and simple intuitive interactions and experience.

#### AUGUST 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016

# Senior Software Engineer/ Tech Mahindra, Pune

Provide full support for business extensive **Telecom Service Provider** by working collaboratively with on site development tram and business analyst and in-house agency teams by providing rapid, robust and client-acclaimed front-end and backend.

- Contributes in **LLD** (Low Level Design) and work collaboratively to create Impact Analysis. Always being an active participant of High Level Design discussion with business.
- Understand existing design patterns to write code suitable with the current context and modify
  design patterns according to the application architecture.
- Document **Impact analysis** and impart KT sessions for any major release.
- Executing **PHP Unit** and writing test cases by encouraging Test Driven Development as a part of development protocol.

#### JUNE 2014 - JUNE 2015

# Software Engineer/ Transparency Market Research, Pune

Develop PHP web application from scratch and enhance existing applications to boost **SEO** which helps generating **leads** for the newly set up market research company.

- Database tuning to enhance performance optimization.
- Design application architecture to support unique meta tags for rapidly changing dynamic contents.
- Develop highly customizable filters to fetch contents in minimal time and lesser number of server calls.

#### DEC 2013 – MAY 2014

## Software Engineer/Plus91 Technologies, Pune

Design, develop and integrate **Social APIs** for **EMR** and **PHR** integrated **health care applications**. Analyzed **FSD** and mentor junior associates to guide throughout application development and deployment cycle.

- Analyze provided FSD and create action plans to get more visibility of the software.
- Exhaustive usage of FET to make application more user friendly, intuitive and single page.
- Impart presentations on any new technical topic on weekly basis to keep growing the learning curve.

## Web Engineer/ Eeshaana Solutions, Pune

SEP 2011 - MARCH 2012

## Web Engineer/ Appeal Soft Pvt Ltd, Pune

#### **Education**

2006 - 2011

**B.E Computer Science/ AISSMS COE, Pune** 

2004

H.S.E / K.V Hinoo, Ranchi

## **Additional Information**

- Received 50 % extra bonus and highest number of appreciation for working as single source multi project development and deployment by achieving deadlines.
- Nominated to train team members to use GIT and Test-Driven Development.
- Participated in IEEE paper presentations.
- Develop SMS based information software using JTAPI using JAVA Voice over WIKI.